# Aquib Vadsaria

# Web Developer

#### **SUMMARY**

Almost 7+ years of experience working as a web developer from past 3 years, full stack developer for 2 years and system engineer for 2 years.

Proficient in Front end technologies majorly around HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript (React.js, Redux, Rx.js).

Career objective and focus is to become a Software Architect while advocating clean code, modern software practices and keep on actively learning new technologies and frameworks.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# J.P. Morgan Chase - Application Developer

NOVEMBER 2016 - PRESENT

- Working as a Senior Front End Developer for FX Trading platform, developing new trading applications and rewriting legacy FLEX trading platform into HTML5.
- Collaborate with global team and contribute through PR process.
- Delivered knowledge transfer session about React and JS ecosystem to Flex Developers.
- Developed internal React component library to be used by various other banking applications.
- Optimized the app build process from 10 mins to 4 mins by running grunt tasks parallel.

Technology stack: React, Redux, Rx.js, ES6, Typescript, GIT, JIRA, Node.js, Webpack, Rollup, Jest, Enzyme, CSS3, HTML5, Grunt, Jasmine.

## Built.io - Web Developer

AUGUST 2015 - OCT 2016

- Worked on **Built.io Flow** web application which is a service orchestration tool for creating complex workflows.
- Major development contribution was to reduce initial loading time from 2 mins to 45 seconds, rewriting existing application from Angular.js to React, adding features like keyboard navigations and shortcuts to main canvas.

🙎 Mumbai, India



+91-9930185246



vadsaria.ak@gmail.com



/aguib-vadsaria



/aqumus



/portfolio

#### **SKILLS**

Proficient: HTML5, CSS3, JS, React.js, Redux, Rx.js, Typescript, GIT, ES6, JSON, AJAX.

Intermediate: Node.js, Express.js, Socket.io, MongoDB, Jest, Mocha, JQuery, Electron, Webpack, Rollup.js, Angular, JS & React profiling, TDD.

Basic: Java, Python, Machine Learning, UNIX, AWS web services, shell scripting, MySQL, Agile methodologies

#### **EDUCATION**

B.E in Electronics and Telecommunication - Mumbai University (2012)

# **CERTIFICATION & COURSES**

Machine Learning, Stanford University - 2017

System X Certified Engineer - 2013

#### **LANGUAGES**

English (fluent)

Hindi (native)

Gujarati(Basic)

- Optimized developer experience by transpiling only changed files using gulp task.
- Mentored Junior developers for React and JS patterns, writing readable code.
- Developed testing framework to test web services and REST API.

Technology stack: React, Flux, ES6, Typescript, GIT, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Gulp, Mocha, Angular.js, AWS.

# IBM India Pvt. Ltd. - System Support Representative

JULY 2012 - AUGUST 2015

- Implemented Enterprise servers, SAN storages and network switches
- Configured servers, hardware and OS level hardening and clustering to be used as High Availability SAP Database server.
- Supported L2 level of breakdown issues and co-ordinated escalated issues with Product Engineer for new firmware updates or hardware fixes.
- Developed Dashboard and admin page for server logging system using HTML5, CSS3, JS and JQuery.

### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

# **RSyncBackup**

Early stage Desktop application for taking files backup. Main objective was to have an UI interface for using rsync commands in Windows WSL.

# **Economic Planning**

Leaded the front end team of volunteers and developed application for NGO which is used to plan economies, funding and to track consultation reviews of various families.

# **Android ROM Testing**

Testing and raising bugs/defects on XDA Developers for nightly build of custom android ROM targeted for mobile devices like HTC HD2, Samsung S3, One Plus one.

#### **HOBBIES**

Reading Tech blogs

Music

Watching TV Shows

#### **CURRENTLY LEARNING**

Python

GraphQL

Angular

**UX** Designing